Citizens Environmental Coalition; Records apap197
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Activities, 1973-2005; 1; 22.35 cubic ft.
  - Labor and the Environment Network, 1989-2001; 1.7; 2.37 cubic ft. and 1 videotape
    - LEN Resources, 1998 (Box 2 (1-Activities), Folder 25)
    - LEN Resources, 1999-2000 (Box 2 (1-Activities), Folder 26)
    - United Steelworkers Hazardous Chemical Training Course Resource Manual, 1991; 5 folders (Box 2 (1-Activities), Folder 27-31)
    - Photographs, Undated; 5 folders (Box 3 (1-Activities), Folder 1-5)
    - Labor and the Environment Retreat, 1992-1993 (Box 4 (1-Activities), Folder 1)
    - LEN, Corporate Welfare Carnival, 2001 (Box 4 (1-Activities), Folder 2)
    - LEN, Workshop and Conference Information, 1989-1997 (Box 4 (1-Activities), Folder 3)
    - LEN, Environmental Information, 1992 (Box 4 (1-Activities), Folder 4)
    - LEN, Program, 1994-1995 (Box 4 (1-Activities), Folder 5)
    - LEN Articles, 1995 (Box 4 (1-Activities), Folder 6)
    - LEN Conference, 1990 (Box 4 (1-Activities), Folder 7)
    - LEN Conference, 1991 (Box 4 (1-Activities), Folder 8)
    - LEN Conference, 1993 (Box 4 (1-Activities), Folder 9)
    - WSTM Channel 3 Syracuse, Editorial, Opposition to Ban on PVC Piping Passed by the New York State Legislature, Described as "Gift" to Organized Labor, ca. 2000; VHS videotape (Video-tape 3)
  - Low Level Radioactive Waste, 1973-1997; 1.8; 4.20 cubic ft.
    The records in this subseries include correspondence, news clippings, research material, and government reports related to low level radioactive waste in New York State. The records reflect activity to discover the health affects of radioactive waste and find safe disposal. The earliest of the research material dates to 1973, but the bulk of CEC activity records are from 1983-1995.
    - LLRW, Committee and Participation Lists, Steps Needed for LLRW Management, 1983 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 1)
    - LLRW, Correspondence with NYS Assembly, 1983 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 2)
    - LLRW, Studies, Newsletters, and Correspondence, 1984 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 3)
    - LLRW, Correspondence with Government Officials, 1984 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 4)
    - LLRW, Testimonies, Statements, 1985 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 5)
    - LLRW, Memorandums and Senate -- Assembly Information, 1985 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 6)
    - LLRW, Nuclear Waste, Memorandums, Correspondence, 1985 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 7)
    - LLRW, Hazardous Waste, Memorandums, Testimonies, 1985 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 8)
    - LLRW, Newsletters, Assembly Correspondence, 1985 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 9)
    - LLRW, Summaries, Assembly Information, Correspondence, 1986 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 10)
    - LLRW, Testimonies, Disposal Facilities, 1987 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 11)
    - LLRW, Assortment of Information, including Proposals, Comments, and the Siting Commission, 1988 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 12)
    - LLRW, Commission Meetings, Attendance Sheets, 1988 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 13)
    - LLRW, News Clip Articles, 1988 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 14)
    - LLRW, "Don't Waste New York", 1989 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 15)
    - LLRW, LLRW Frontline, "Developing a New York State Plan", 1989 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 16)
    - LLRW, Correspondence, Information on Waste, 1989 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 17)
    - LLRW, Correspondence and Flyers, 1989 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 18)
    - LLRW, Programs, Waste Disposal, Correspondence, 1989 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 19)
    - LLRW, Commission Meetings and News Clippings, 1989 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 20)
    - LLRW, 1989 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 21)
    - LLRW, 1990; 4 folders (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 22-25)
    - LLRW, 1990; 2 folders (Box 2 (1-Activities), Folder 1-2)
    - LLRW, 1991; 4 folders (Box 2 (1-Activities), Folder 3-6)
    - LLRW, 1992; 4 folders (Box 2 (1-Activities), Folder 7-10)
    - LLRW, 1993; 4 folders (Box 2 (1-Activities), Folder 11-14)
    - LLRW, 1994; 3 folders (Box 2 (1-Activities), Folder 15-17)
    - LLRW, 1995 (Box 2 (1-Activities), Folder 18)
    - LLRW, 1996-1997; 2001 (Box 2 (1-Activities), Folder 19)
    - On-Site Reactor Storage, 1985-1995; 4 folders (Box 2 (1-Activities), Folder 20-23)
    - Redefinition LLRW, 1983-1989 (Box 2 (1-Activities), Folder 24)
    - West Valley Site (New York), Undated; 2 folders (Box 2 (1-Activities), Folder 25-26)
    - LLRW, 1983 (Box 3 (1-Activities), Folder 1)
    - LLRW, 1984 (Box 3 (1-Activities), Folder 2)
    - LLRW, 1985 (Box 3 (1-Activities), Folder 3)
    - LLRW, 1986 (Box 3 (1-Activities), Folder 4)
    - LLRW, 1988 (Box 3 (1-Activities), Folder 5)
    - LLRW, 1989 (Box 3 (1-Activities), Folder 6)
    - LLRW, 1990 (Box 3 (1-Activities), Folder 7)
    - LLRW, 1991 (Box 3 (1-Activities), Folder 8)
    - LLRW, 1992 (Box 3 (1-Activities), Folder 9)
    - LLRW, 1993 (Box 3 (1-Activities), Folder 10)
    - LLRW, 1994 (Box 3 (1-Activities), Folder 11)
    - Annual Report of Environmental Radiation in New York State, 1973; 1975 (Box 4 (1-Activities), Folder 1)
    - Concerns Regarding the National Academy of Sciences' Review of New York State Low-Level Radioactive Waste Sitting Process, 1994 February (Box 4 (1-Activities), Folder 2)
    - Conference on Public Health Considerations For Low-Level Radioactive Waste Disposal in New York State, 1987 March 19-1987 March 20 (Box 4 (1-Activities), Folder 3)
    - Deadly Defense: Military Radioactive Landfills, 1988 (Box 4 (1-Activities), Folder 4)
    - Environmental Radiation in New York State, 1982-1985 (Box 4 (1-Activities), Folder 5)
    - Environmental Radiation in New York State, 1986 (Box 4 (1-Activities), Folder 6)
    - Environmental Radiation in New York State, 1987; 1988 (Box 4 (1-Activities), Folder 7)
    - Generic Scope of Draft Environmental Impact Statement, 1988 September (Box 4 (1-Activities), Folder 8)
    - Handbook of Disposal Technologies for Low-Level Radioactive Waste, 1987 June (Box 4 (1-Activities), Folder 9)
    - Handbook of Disposal Technologies for Low-Level Radioactive Waste, 1987 June (Box 4 (1-Activities), Folder 10)
    - High-Level Dollars, Low-Level Sense, 1992 (Box 4 (1-Activities), Folder 11)
    - Living Without Landfills, 1987 (Box 4 (1-Activities), Folder 12)
    - LLRW Resources, 1995 (Box 4 (1-Activities), Folder 13)
    - LLRW Summary Article, 1997 (Box 4 (1-Activities), Folder 14)
    - LLRW Transport Reports, 1960-1992 (Box 4 (1-Activities), Folder 15)
    - Low-Level Radioactive Waste Management in New York, 1988 September (Box 4 (1-Activities), Folder 16)
    - New York State Low-Level Radioactive Waste Management Study, Volume One, 1984 April (Box 4 (1-Activities), Folder 17)
    - New York State Low-Level Radioactive Waste Management Study, Volume Two, 1984 April (Box 4 (1-Activities), Folder 18)
    - New York State Low-Level Radioactive Waste Management Study, Volume Three, 1984 April (Box 4 (1-Activities), Folder 19)
    - New York State Low-Level Radioactive Waste Status Report, 1987 (Box 4 (1-Activities), Folder 20)
    - Plan for Selecting Sites for Disposal of Low-Level Radioactive Wastes, 1988 November (Box 4 (1-Activities), Folder 21)
    - Radiation and Health Information, Undated; 3 folders (Box 4 (1-Activities), Folder 22-24)
    - Radiation Induced Cancer, 1990 (Box 4 (1-Activities), Folder 25)
    - Radiation Regulation and Protection in New York State, 1985 January (Box 4 (1-Activities), Folder 26)
    - Radioactive Medical Waste, 1994 (Box 4 (1-Activities), Folder 27)
    - Radioactivity in Air, Milk, and Water, 1975-1979 (Box 4 (1-Activities), Folder 28)
    - Recommendations for Assistance to Localities, 1988 April (Box 4 (1-Activities), Folder 29)
    - Recommendations for State Assistance to Localities Affected by the Sitting of Low-Level Radioactive Waste Management Facility, 1987 April (Box 4 (1-Activities), Folder 30)
    - Secrecy, Money, and Deception: The Attempt to Site West Valley, 1991 November (Box 4 (1-Activities), Folder 31)
    - Statewide Exclusionary Screening Report, 1988 September (Box 4 (1-Activities), Folder 32)
    - The U.S. Military's Toxic Legacy, 1991 (Box 4 (1-Activities), Folder 33)
    - 6 NYCRR Part 382, 1987 December (Box 5 (1-Activities), Folder 1)
    - Developing a New York State Plan for Interim Management of Low-Level Radioactive Waste, 1989 January 30 (Box 5 (1-Activities), Folder 2)
    - Disposal Method Evaluation Procedures, 1994 March (Box 5 (1-Activities), Folder 3)
    - Environmental Radiation in New York State, 1990-1991 (Box 5 (1-Activities), Folder 4)
    - Environmental Radiation in New York State, 1992 (Box 5 (1-Activities), Folder 5)
    - Environmental Radiation in New York State, 1993 (Box 5 (1-Activities), Folder 6)
    - Executive Summary, 6 NYCRR Part 382, 1987 December (Box 5 (1-Activities), Folder 7)
    - Executive Summary - Disposal Method Screening Report, 1989 July (Box 5 (1-Activities), Folder 8)
    - Executive Summary Report on Potential Sites Identification, 1989 September (Box 5 (1-Activities), Folder 9)
    - Executive Summary - Source Term Report: Low-Level Radioactive Waste Projections for New York, 1989 July (Box 5 (1-Activities), Folder 10)
    - Final Environmental Impact Statement, Volume 1, 6 NYCRR Part 382, 1987 December (Box 5 (1-Activities), Folder 11)
    - Final Environmental Impact Statement, Volume 2, 6 NYCRR Part 382, 1987 December (Box 5 (1-Activities), Folder 12)
    - Final Generic Environmental Impact Statement for 6 NYCRR Part 382, Volume I, 1993 January (Box 5 (1-Activities), Folder 13)
    - Final Generic Environmental Impact Statement for 6 NYCRR Part 382, Volume II, 1993 January (Box 5 (1-Activities), Folder 14)
    - Generic Site Characteristics Report, 1994 June (Box 5 (1-Activities), Folder 15)
    - Low-Level Radioactive Waste Storage Study, Volume I, 1993 October (Box 5 (1-Activities), Folder 16)
    - Low-Level Radioactive Waste Storage Study, Volume II, 1993 October (Box 5 (1-Activities), Folder 17)
    - Nuclear Waste: New York's Adherence to Site Selection Procedures is Unclear, 1992 August (Box 5 (1-Activities), Folder 18)
    - NYS Low-Level Radioactive Waste Siting Commission Program Report, 1994 (Box 5 (1-Activities), Folder 19)
    - Plan for Selecting a Preferred Method for Disposal of Low-Level Radioactive Wastes, 1993 July (Box 5 (1-Activities), Folder 20)
    - Proposed Disposal Method Conceptual Design Report, 1994 June (Box 5 (1-Activities), Folder 21)
    - Response to Public Comments Relating to the Report on Potential Sites Identification, 1992 November (Box 5 (1-Activities), Folder 22)
    - Revisions to Proposed 6 NYCRR Part 382 and Revisions to Proposed Amendments to 6 NYCRR Parts 382 and 380, 1992 August (Box 5 (1-Activities), Folder 23)
  - 9/11/01 Environmental Issues, 2001-2002; 1.9; 0.17 cubic ft.
    This series contains materials about the environmental consequences of the 9/11/01 terrorist attacks. It contains articles, a guide, a report, and correspondence.
    - 9/11/2001, Environmental Issues, 2001-2002 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 1)
  - Governor George Pataki Environmental Record, 1994-1996; 1.10; 0.17 cubic ft.
    This subseries contains reports, news releases, papers, and news clippings that comment on the environmental record of Governor George Pataki's administration.
    - Pataki Environmental Record, 1994-1996 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 1)
  - Superfund, 1984-2002; 1.11; 0.40 cubic ft.
    The records in this subseries include publications, fact sheets, news clippings, legislative material related to the Superfund, and Superfund financing in New York State. Additional records in this series are actively being used at CEC and will be transferred in the future.
    - Brownfields, 1996-2001 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 1)
    - Hazardous Substances List, 1984 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 2)
    - No Time to Lose, 1990 May (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 3)
    - NYSBA 2001 Legislative Forum (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 4)
    - Superfund, 1984-2001 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 5)
    - Superfund, 1991-2002 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 6)
    - Superfund, 1992-2002 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 7)
    - Superfund, 2001 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 8)
    - Superfund Proposals, 2002 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 9)
    - Superfund Resources, 1985-2001 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 10)
    - Tools for Action, 1987 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 11)
    - Tools for Action, 1987 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 12)
  - Toxics, 1983-2002; 1.12; 2.4 cubic ft.
    These records include correspondence, news clippings, newsletters and other publications related to toxic chemicals and pollution in New York State. Lobbying and outreach records document CEC efforts to pressure the New York State Department of Health to investigate the health effects of toxic pollution and to pressure the New York State Department of Environmental Conservation to clean up toxic waste and prosecute polluters.
    - Birth Defects Study, 1989-1994 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 1)
    - The Department of Environmental Conservation...a Program and Budget History, 1985 January (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 2)
    - DOH and CEC, 1983-1991 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 3)
    - DOH and CEC, 1992-1999; 3 folders (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 4-6)
    - DOH Environmental Health Information Kit, 1991 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 7)
    - Enforcement Campaigns, 1984-1994; 3 folders (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 8-10)
    - Right-to-Know, 2001-2002; 2 folders (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 11-12)
    - Toxics, 1990-2002 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 13)
    - Toxics Coalition, 1983 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 14)
    - Toxics Coalition, 1984; 2 folders (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 15-16)
    - Toxics Coalition, 1985 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 17)
    - Toxics Coalition, 1986; 2 folders (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 18-19)
    - Toxics Coalition, 1987 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 20)
    - Toxics Coalition, 1988 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 21)
    - Toxics Coalition, 1989; 2 folders (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 22-23)
    - Toxics and Department of Health, 1983-1992; 3 folders (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 24-26)
    - Ward Stone, Budget, 1986-1996 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 27)
    - CECOS Landfill, 1990 (Box 2 (1-Activities), Folder 1)
    - A Citizen's Guide to Hazardous Waste Technologies and Resources, 1989 (Box 2 (1-Activities), Folder 2)
    - DEC Budget Campaign, 1987-1995 (Box 2 (1-Activities), Folder 3)
    - DEC Commissioner's Meeting, 1988 (Box 2 (1-Activities), Folder 4)
    - DEC Complaint Forms, 1998; 1994; 2 folders (Box 2 (1-Activities), Folder 5-6)
    - DEC Regulatory Reform, 1993-1994 (Box 2 (1-Activities), Folder 7)
    - DEC Regulatory Reform, 1995; 2 folders (Box 2 (1-Activities), Folder 8-9)
    - DEET Campaign, 1991 (Box 2 (1-Activities), Folder 10)
    - Hazardous Waste Transportation, 1988 (Box 2 (1-Activities), Folder 11)
    - Help! Give Earth a Chance, 1972 (Box 2 (1-Activities), Folder 12)
    - Lead Ban, 1992 (Box 2 (1-Activities), Folder 13)
    - Not in Anyone's Backyard Conference, 1992 November 07 (Box 2 (1-Activities), Folder 14)
    - OMH Corp, Mobile Incinerator, 1991 (Box 2 (1-Activities), Folder 15)
    - OXY Incinerator, 1986 (Box 2 (1-Activities), Folder 16)
    - Part 378 Regulations, 1991-1994; 2 folders (Box 2 (1-Activities), Folder 17-18)
    - Poisoning Property: The Impact of Toxics on California's Economy, 1985 (Box 2 (1-Activities), Folder 19)
    - Reducing Toxic Wastes, 1991 (Box 2 (1-Activities), Folder 20)
    - School Siting Proposal, 1988 (Box 2 (1-Activities), Folder 21)
    - Toxic Waste Reduction, 1986-1992 (Box 2 (1-Activities), Folder 22)
    - Toxic Waste Reduction Resources, 1986-1995 (Box 2 (1-Activities), Folder 23)
    - Toxic Waste Siting, 1985-1987 (Box 2 (1-Activities), Folder 24)
    - Toxic Waste Siting, 1988-1990; 2 folders (Box 2 (1-Activities), Folder 25-26)
    - Toxic Waste Siting, 1991; 2 folders (Box 2 (1-Activities), Folder 27-28)
    - Toxic Waste Siting, 1993-1994 (Box 2 (1-Activities), Folder 29)
    - Toxic Waste Siting, 2002 (Box 2 (1-Activities), Folder 30)
    - Toxic Waste Siting, Final New York State Hazardous Waste Facility Siting Plan (Draft) and Generic Environmental Impact Statement, 1991 September (Box 2 (1-Activities), Folder 31)
    - Toxics in Your Community Coalition Membership List, 1989 (Box 2 (1-Activities), Folder 32)
    - Toxics in Your Community Newsletters, 1985-1993 (Box 2 (1-Activities), Folder 33)
    - Where Can the Children Play? A Report on Long Island's Priority Environmental Hazards & A Directory of Long Island Environmental Organizations, 1993 May (Box 2 (1-Activities), Folder 34)
    - CECOS Landfill, 1990 (Box 3 (1-Activities), Folder 1)
    - DEC Budget Campaign, 1987-1995 (Box 3 (1-Activities), Folder 2)
    - DEC Complaint Forms, 1988; 1994; 2 folders (Box 3 (1-Activities), Folder 3-4)
    - Enforcement Campaigns, 1984-1994 (Box 3 (1-Activities), Folder 5)
    - Environmental Quality Bond Act, 1986 (Box 3 (1-Activities), Folder 6)
    - OXY Incinerator, 1986 (Box 3 (1-Activities), Folder 7)
    - Part 378 Regulations, 1991-1994 (Box 3 (1-Activities), Folder 8)
    - Toxics Coalition, 1984 (Box 3 (1-Activities), Folder 9)
    - Toxics Coalition, 1985 (Box 3 (1-Activities), Folder 10)
    - Toxics Coalition, 1986-1987 (Box 3 (1-Activities), Folder 11)
    - Toxics Coalition, 1988 (Box 3 (1-Activities), Folder 12)
    - Toxics Coalition, 1989 (Box 3 (1-Activities), Folder 13)
    - Toxics Coalition, 1990 (Box 3 (1-Activities), Folder 14)
    - Toxics in Your Community Newsletters, 1985-1993 (Box 3 (1-Activities), Folder 15)
    - Toxic Waste Siting, 1988-1990 (Box 3 (1-Activities), Folder 16)
    - Toxic Waste Siting, 1993-1994 (Box 3 (1-Activities), Folder 17)
    - Ward Stone Budget, 1986-1996 (Box 3 (1-Activities), Folder 18)
  - Water, 1987-2000; 1.13; 1.17 cubic ft.
    The records in this subseries include planning documents, workshop material, government water regulation, clean water legislation, as well as meeting and conference files. These records discuss clean water activism and the Source Water Assessment Program in New York State. Most of the records originated with the Western New York Office of CEC.
    - A Citizen's Guide to Preventing Groundwater Pollution, 1997 Fall (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 1)
    - Contacts at Bureau of Public Water Supply Protection, 1997 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 2)
    - Coordinating Committee, 1997-1998 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 3)
    - Diane Hemingway Comments and Testimony, 1997-1998 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 4)
    - DOH Chemical Contamination, 1992 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 5)
    - Drinking Water, 1994-1995 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 6)
    - EPA SWAP Guidance, 1997 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 7)
    - Ground Water Resources, 1996 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 8)
    - Ground Water Resources, 1997 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous, 1992-1998; Undated (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 10)
    - New York State 303d List, 1998 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 11)
    - New York State SWAP Focus Group Meetings, 1997 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 12)
    - New York State Source Water Assessment Program Plan, 1999 February 06 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 13)
    - New York State Source Water Assessment Program Plan, 1999 November (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 14)
    - Partial List of Potential Sources of Contamination, Undated (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 15)
    - Public Participation Assessment Format Work Group Meeting, 1998 February 25 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 16)
    - Safe Drinking Water Act Amendments of 1996 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 17)
    - Safe Drinking Water Bill, 1987-1993 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 18)
    - Small Towns Environmental Program, 1993-1998 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 19)
    - Source Protection, 1996 March (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 20)
    - Source Water Protection Coordinating Committee Meeting, 1998 April 01 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 21)
    - Support Packet for Source Water Assessment Program Meetings, 1998 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 22)
    - SWAP, 1996-1999 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 23)
    - SWAP, 1997-2000 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 24)
    - SWAP, 1998 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 25)
    - SWAP, 1998-1999 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 26)
    - SWAP, 2000, Undated (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 27)
    - SWAP Clearinghouse, 1988-2001; Undated (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 28)
    - SWAP Conference, 1998 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 29)
    - SWAP Email List, 1998 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 30)
    - SWAP and EPA, 1999-2000 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 31)
    - Water, 1997-2002 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 32)
    - Water Management Advisory Committee, 1997-1998 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 33)
    - Water Policy Advocacy, 1985-1997 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 34)
    - Water Resources, 1981-1988 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 35)
    - Water Resources, 2003 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 36)
    - Workshops, 1996-1998 (Box 1 (1-Activities), Folder 37)
    - Hudson Valley Green Times, Special Feature - Water, Vol. 22, No. 3, 2002 (Box 2 (1-Activities), Folder 1)
    - Lake Champlain Basin, 2002-2003 (Box 2 (1-Activities), Folder 2)
    - Lake George Watershed, 2001-2003 (Box 2 (1-Activities), Folder 3)
    - Safe Water Drinking Bill, 1987-1993 (Box 2 (1-Activities), Folder 4)
    - Water Policy Advocacy, 1985-1997 (Box 2 (1-Activities), Folder 5)
- Administrative Files, 1987-2002; 2; 1.17 cubic ft.
  This series contains correspondence, notes, news clippings relating to CEC, reports, financial documents, and other administrative records of CEC. It also contains CEC founding and structural records. Most of the materials in this series are arranged chronologically.
  Arranged alphabetically and chronologically.
  - Board of Directors, 2002 (Box 1 (2-Administrative Files), Folder 1)
  - CEC Organization, 1990-1991 (Box 1 (2-Administrative Files), Folder 2)
  - Contacts, 1999-2003 (Box 1 (2-Administrative Files), Folder 3)
  - Environmental Hazards Information, 2001-2003 (Box 1 (2-Administrative Files), Folder 4)
  - General Office Files, 1990; 3 folders (Box 1 (2-Administrative Files), Folder 5-7)
  - General Office Files, 1991; 3 folders (Box 1 (2-Administrative Files), Folder 8-10)
  - General Office Files, 1992; 2 folders (Box 1 (2-Administrative Files), Folder 11-12)
  - General Office Files, 1993 (Box 1 (2-Administrative Files), Folder 13)
  - General Office Files, 1994; 2 folders (Box 1 (2-Administrative Files), Folder 14-15)
  - General Office Files, 1995 (Box 1 (2-Administrative Files), Folder 16)
  - General Office Files, 1996 (Box 1 (2-Administrative Files), Folder 17)
  - General Office Files, 1997 (Box 1 (2-Administrative Files), Folder 18)
  - Membership / Recruitment, 1992; 2000 (Box 1 (2-Administrative Files), Folder 19)
  - Strategic Planning, 2000-2002 (Box 1 (2-Administrative Files), Folder 20)
  - General Office Files, 1982 (Box 2 (2-Administrative Files), Folder 1)
  - General Office Files, 1991 (Box 2 (2-Administrative Files), Folder 2)
  - General Office Files, 1992 (Box 2 (2-Administrative Files), Folder 3)
  - General Office Files, 1993 (Box 2 (2-Administrative Files), Folder 4)
- Fundraising, 1985-2004; 3; 2.0 cubic ft.
  This series contains fundraising records, particularly those connected to the foundations that fund CEC. It contains grant records, tracking of major individual donors, and canvassing records. This includes correspondence, notes, grant applications, reports, budgets, statistics, and raw data.
  - Beldon Fund, 1987-1996 (Box 1 (3-Fundraising), Folder 1)
  - Canvassing, Budget, 1991-1994 (Box 1 (3-Fundraising), Folder 2)
  - Canvassing, Weekly Reports, 1992 (Box 1 (3-Fundraising), Folder 3)